[{"id": "600398b657a0e35c43f8389d", "question": "James McNeill Whistler's Arrangement in Grey and Black No.1 is better known by what other name?", "answer": "Whistler's Mother\u00a0-- It is exhibited in the Mus\u00e9e d'Orsay in Paris, having been bought by the French state in 1891.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5e72ce4cd0874f1a5e2d1c27", "question": "Which prominent US statesman was known as \"The Great Compromiser\" and helped allegedly swing the 1824 election?", "answer": "Henry Clay", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395f5", "question": "In The Simpsons, what platoon was Abe Simpson in charge of during WWII?", "answer": "The Flying Hellfish", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe909eb01dd7bf43be5e893", "question": "What is trepanning?", "answer": "The drilling of holes in the head and scraping or cutting of the skull", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b9c", "question": "What 2004 film spawned a line of popular t-shirts reading \"Vote for Pedro\"?", "answer": "Napoleon Dynamite", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe8aa0e01dd7bf43be5e756", "question": "What gets wetter and wetter the more it dries?", "answer": "A towel", "category": "general"}, {"id": "60078be90eee65b76b9f266e", "question": "In which country did the first World War I battle take place?", "answer": "Belgium (The first official battle of WWI occurred at the city named Liege. The city was taken by Germany by August 15, 1914.)", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c2e7", "question": "What is the longest insect?", "answer": "The walking stick", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339eb7", "question": "What made-up expletive is \"Battlestar Galactica's\" dirty word of choice?", "answer": "Frak", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5b3236bdbf195a31e15d73be", "question": "\"Oliver's Story\" was the sequel to which best-seller by Erich Segal?", "answer": "Love Story", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fede5cf6ce05a3942286df1", "question": "Which of Santa's reindeer is female?", "answer": "Vixen", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133adbc", "question": "Which country was split into zones by the 'Yalta Agreement'?", "answer": "Germany", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a7d4", "question": "What is the largest island in the Mediterranean Sea?", "answer": "Sicily", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c3ae", "question": "What name is given to rain with a particularly low pH?", "answer": "Acid rain", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a7fc", "question": "Off the coast of what continent will you find the Strait of Magellan?", "answer": "South America", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59029f42cad1ec93f27df75d", "question": "Which empire gave the world the Pilsner?", "answer": "The Austrian Empire", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ccf7a52b37b32637bdc44c0", "question": "What is the first foreign country you will reach if you go south from Miami, Florida.", "answer": "Cuba", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe69aab20565ad31a57c756", "question": "In the Bible, who is the wife of Boaz?", "answer": "Ruth", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "58bb3522e368446ca7bd684f", "question": "What chemical reaction during roasting is chiefly responsible for giving green coffee beans their flavor?", "answer": "Maillard Reaction", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d5b", "question": "The shoe-obsessed Spats Colombo is the villain of what 1959 comedy?", "answer": "Some Like It Hot", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5febb0ce7e83c707845b2108", "question": "What insect protects peonies from damaging pests?", "answer": "Ants", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a4b4", "question": "What is the only nation that borders both Andorra and Portugal?", "answer": "Spain", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b060", "question": "When did the Panama Canal open?", "answer": "1914", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5906814dff9c0647b50a8093", "question": "How old was novelist Harper Lee at the time of her death in February, 2016?", "answer": "89", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133aefd", "question": "What did explorer Robert Peary attempt to reach in 1909?", "answer": "The North Pole", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5b3236ecbf195a31e15d73c0", "question": "What do you call a boxer who leads with his right?", "answer": "A Southpaw", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ab99acb21a8909e5c332d23", "question": "The Kelvin scale is used to measure what?", "answer": "Temperature", "category": "science"}, {"id": "597cdba7e347d002c297e4df", "question": "What do the letters stand for in poet E.E. Cummings' name?", "answer": "Edward Estlin", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c02", "question": "What is actor Jack Nicholson's full birthname?", "answer": "John Joseph Nicholson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c63b", "question": "Which blood type is a universal? donor", "answer": "O negative", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391a0", "question": "What movie starred Johnny Depp as Willy Wonka?", "answer": "Charlie and the Chocolate Factory", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c5e1", "question": "What name is given to the study of the behavior and flow of air around objects?", "answer": "Aerodynamics", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339448", "question": "Who directed the 1941 movie \"The Lady Eve\"?", "answer": "Preston Sturges", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c8ec", "question": "What is the study of production of materials at low temperatures called?", "answer": "Cryogenics", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133acf5", "question": "Which state was the first to ratify the 13th Amendment to abolish slavery?", "answer": "Illinois", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a2b1", "question": "Frank Oz performed the character of which Muppet until the early 2000's?", "answer": "Miss Piggy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f74", "question": "Who was the first novelist to present a typed manuscript to his publisher?", "answer": "Mark Twain", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c1c2", "question": "Which politician is known as Tarzan?", "answer": "Michael Heseltine", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e7b", "question": "Which TV show used the song \"Here with Me\" by Dido as its theme song?", "answer": "Roswell", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b1bc", "question": "What Manhattan intersection was America's first transfer circle?", "answer": "Columbus Circle", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc6a", "question": "How many Super Bowl appearances did Brett Favre lead as part of the Green Bay Packers?", "answer": "2", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b604", "question": "What war do the girls in \"Little Women\" grow up during?", "answer": "The Civil War", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fede4946ce05a3942286dde", "question": "Which American tennis player popularized metal rackets by first using a Wilson T2000?", "answer": "Jimmy Connors", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59049cd4cf93664eb10486aa", "question": "What is the name of the avenue that lies between 12th and 14th Avenue in San Francisco?", "answer": "Funston Avenue", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133acff", "question": "What building first appeared on the back of a $20 bill in 1928?", "answer": "The White House", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b0e0", "question": "During which war did the flag flying above Fort McHenry inspire Francis Scott Key's \"The Star-Spangled Banner\"?", "answer": "War of 1812", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a2eb", "question": "What year did the band Human League release an album titled \"Dare\"?", "answer": "1981", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59db77f10ab2c8f322317ff1", "question": "Which tennis star wore denim shorts during matches?", "answer": "Andre Agassi", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c007", "question": "Parasitophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Parasites", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133cacc", "question": "Which bone is known as the Patella?", "answer": "The kneecap", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ef8", "question": "What's Mick Jagger's favorite soda, according to \"You Can't Always Get What You Want\"?", "answer": "Cherry red", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b81d", "question": "What year was the lava lamp launched?", "answer": "1965", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c6a", "question": "What movie helped popularize disco music worldwide?", "answer": "Saturday Night Fever", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be2d", "question": "In what country did Red Bull originate as Krating Daeng?", "answer": "Thailand", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f22", "question": "In a symphony orchestra, what instrument is played by the concertmaster?", "answer": "Violin", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c651", "question": "How many daily tides are there?", "answer": "Two", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59e6b7a3fb6c85e9e634ff4c", "question": "Which comet is visible every 74 to 79 years?", "answer": "Halley's comet", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe768c8eec85e375820b2a7", "question": "The Ghirardelli Chocolate Company was founded in which city?", "answer": "San Francisco, California", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113396d0", "question": "Who won the first season of the TV series \"American Idol\"?", "answer": "Kelly Clarkson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "60062cc2c9d816e292245c2e", "question": "To which artistic movement does Paul Gauguin's The Yellow Christ belong?", "answer": "The Yellow Christ\u00a0is a painting that depicts the crucifixion. The techniques used in this painting are typical of\u00a0cloisonnism.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113393e1", "question": "What Broadway musical featured \"The Telephone Hour\"?", "answer": "Bye Bye Birdie", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe8f3f101dd7bf43be5e81b", "question": "SNAP stands for what in the US?", "answer": "Supplemental Nutrition Assistance Program", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c6b2", "question": "The hottest natural chemical according to the Scoville Scale, resiniferatoxin, comes from what plant?", "answer": "Resin spurge", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133aeea", "question": "In which war was the \"Battle of Ramillies\"?", "answer": "War of Spanish Succession", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c7cf", "question": "In 1986, a brittle O-ring seal was determined to be the cause of what?", "answer": "The Challenger disaster", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b594", "question": "When was the game \"Scrabble\" first released?", "answer": "1948", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe3efeb8b5801b8f54a7fb8", "question": "Which software giant was founded in Albuquerque, New Mexico in 1975?", "answer": "Microsoft", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133905b", "question": "Once married to Ted Hughes, which American poet committed suicide in 1963?", "answer": "Sylvia Plath", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a39", "question": "What poet penned \"Ash Wednesday\" in 1930?", "answer": "T.S. Eliot", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c16d", "question": "What's the international radio code word for the letter \"M\"?", "answer": "Mike", "category": "general"}, {"id": "594d06d21a1c922dd1ac64b0", "question": "What is the oldest bridge over the river Seine in Paris?", "answer": "Pont Neuf", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe65619ae7e414034b5aec0", "question": "What was Atlas famously forced to do by the Greek gods?", "answer": "Hold the Heavens on his shoulders", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fd2d80a2596a59cbdfbd3be", "question": "Which ancient wonder was burned down by a fame-seeking arsonist?", "answer": "Artemis", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c7ad", "question": "What is the proper name of the flower more commonly referred to as \"dandelion\"?", "answer": "Taraxacum", "category": "science"}, {"id": "58dba40a874c93a3298b2142", "question": "Puccini's \"Tosca\" is based on which 1887 Victorien Sardou play?", "answer": "La Tosca", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c641", "question": "What is a group of lions called?", "answer": " A pride", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe4e70006d333868d34d738", "question": "How many specific commandments regulating aspects of people's lives are there in the Bible in the Mosaic Law?", "answer": "613", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe6a9ec20565ad31a57c80d", "question": "The Nazi organization NSDAP stands for what?", "answer": "National German Workers' Party (Nationalsozialistische Deutsche Arbeiterparteiz)", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c78e", "question": "Who is credited with designing the modern zipper as we know it and use it today?", "answer": "Gideon Sundback", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5b571bb967df192a942e336c", "question": "In the novel \"Goldfinger\", who is the boss of \"The Cement Mixers\" gang?", "answer": "Pussy Galore", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113392f4", "question": "In the movie \"Jurassic Park\", what animal was used to lure the T-Rex?", "answer": "A goat", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113397cc", "question": "What was Marlon Brando's screen name in \"The Godfather\"?", "answer": "Vito Corleone", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6015e859fe83fe1f2a824bdb", "question": "Which English king built castles in the 13th century to help conquer Wales?", "answer": "Edward I", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391b1", "question": "Who played the female lead role in the 2007 movie \"Stardust\"?", "answer": "Claire Danes", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be3d", "question": "How many players are there in a standard quidditch team?", "answer": "Seven", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5904a0decf93664eb10486bb", "question": "The \"Ugu Youth\" radio station is broadcast in which African country?", "answer": "South Africa", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a20b", "question": "Who sang the song \"Californication\"?", "answer": "Red Hot Chilli Peppers", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c39d", "question": "What is the proper term for a young whale?", "answer": "A calf", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339251", "question": "What band performed the Bond theme song \"A View to a Kill\"?", "answer": "Duran Duran", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe909b101dd7bf43be5e890", "question": "What is the outside covering of a plant's root called?", "answer": "Root epidermis", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5909ccedbb53d1af658864e5", "question": "What branch of Christianity introduced the Advent calendar?", "answer": "German Lutherans", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf2f", "question": "What got its name from a Bridgeport pie company's name and lightweight pie tins?", "answer": "Frisbees", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc85", "question": "What political figure is married to former \"In Living Color\" star Alexandra Wentworth?", "answer": "George Stephanopoulos", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c915", "question": "Which element has the atomic number of 12?", "answer": "Magnesium", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba8e", "question": "What type of leaf is depicted on the national flag of Canada?", "answer": "A maple leaf", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c488", "question": "Where is the tragus located on a human body?", "answer": "Near the ear", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5937ee0308d98002fdd633cf", "question": "What is a strong aversion to beards known as?", "answer": "Pogonophobia", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c0b8", "question": "What unusual ingredient is often included in a Gibson cocktail?", "answer": "Pickled onion", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bafc", "question": "The clarinet is a member of what family of instruments?", "answer": "Woodwinds", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a333", "question": "What animal is on the cover of the Beach Boys' album \"Pet Sounds\"?", "answer": "Goat", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c9b9", "question": "The nest of an eagle or bird of prey is called a what?", "answer": "Eyrie", "category": "science"}, {"id": "597ddd3e77980686f722d17d", "question": "When was the first permanent photograph taken?", "answer": "1826", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113393ca", "question": "What David Guterson novel was made into a 1999 motion picture?", "answer": "Snow Falling on Cedars", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133948b", "question": "Who directed the movie \"Leaving Las Vegas\"?", "answer": "Mike Figgis", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6015e963fe83fe1f2a824be5", "question": "Who is Temujin better known as?", "answer": "Genghis Khan", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ccf7944b37b32637bdc44bd", "question": "Who was Cesare Borgia's father?", "answer": "Pope Alexander VI", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58c9f84fb4e2c7fbd3896751", "question": "What is champagne substituted with to turn a \u201cBlack Velvet\u201d cocktail into a \u201cPoor Man\u2019s Black Velvet\u201d cocktail?", "answer": "Cider", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c3e1", "question": "What plastic did John Wesley Hyatt invent by combining cellulose and alcoholized camphor?", "answer": "Celluloid", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5941259dbab1e6f9796f1b55", "question": "What two colors are on the flag of Israel?", "answer": "Blue and white", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b92b", "question": "What article of attire is known as a \"corset\" around police precincts?", "answer": "Bulletproof Vest", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58c8a50e90aac110e4167070", "question": "What is Homer Simpson\u2019s beer of choice?", "answer": "Duff", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5f95aea455722f97b22684d5", "question": "Which Star Wars character is the first to be partially named after director George Lucas\u2019 son?", "answer": "Dexter Jettster", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5b358a485db0d66a186cb552", "question": "Which countries does Bangladesh share a land border with?", "answer": "India and Myanmar (Burma)", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "58f564fc33a95c66dc4fe753", "question": "What is the connection between Johnny Logan and Sean Sherrard?", "answer": "They are the same person", "category": "general"}, {"id": "60062ac3c9d816e292245c1b", "question": "What American artist is known for the Nurse Paintings?", "answer": "The Nurse Paintings are a series by Richard Prince inspired by the covers and titles of pulp romance novels.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59008ca4cf842fa4c4ba96a0", "question": "What is Jimmy Carter's middle name?", "answer": "Earl", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6015df07fe83fe1f2a824b76", "question": "What revolution resulted in the overthrow of the Pahlavi dynasty?", "answer": "The Iranian Revolution", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339795", "question": "What was Mohammed Ali said to float like?", "answer": "A butterfly", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fef66126ce05a3942286e75", "question": "What state inspired Joni Mitchell's \"Big Yellow Taxi\"?", "answer": "Hawaii", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b44f", "question": "What nickname did the Western press give to members of the Fists of Righteous Harmony in China?", "answer": "Boxers", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b9d4", "question": "How many rings are on the Olympic flag?", "answer": "Five", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ada1", "question": "Harry Alonzo Longabaugh was better known as who?", "answer": "Sundance Kid", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b780", "question": "What city's Summer Olympics had the beaver Amik as their mascot?", "answer": "Montreal's", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5901d8fb709c1c34536e6ea8", "question": "In what year did the Ultimate Fighting Championship start?", "answer": "1993", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d0e", "question": "What literary character lived at 221B Baker Street?", "answer": "Sherlock Holmes", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b523", "question": "What is the main difference between a supercharger and a turbocharger?", "answer": "Superchargers are usually belt driven, while turbochargers gas driven.", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133921b", "question": "What instrument did Sting play with the band \"The Police\"?", "answer": "Bass guitar", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c591", "question": "What important sensory organ do earthworms lack?", "answer": "Eyes", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b9c2", "question": "Game Developer Studio \"Naughty Dog\" was first well recognized for which video game franchise?", "answer": "Crash Bandicoot", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6018bc25d96d05b23b281653", "question": "\"An eye for an eye and a tooth for a tooth\" is a well-known phrase from what collection of 282 laws?", "answer": "The Code of Hammurabi", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f6e", "question": "What can be a font, architectural style or novel type?", "answer": "Gothic", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0c8", "question": "Which TV character owns a talking cat called Salem?", "answer": "Sabrina Spellman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b93", "question": "Who is Becky Thatcher's boyfriend?", "answer": "Tom Sawyer", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113394fa", "question": "In the movie \"The Big Lebowski\", what item did the Dude take from the Big Lebowski mansion as compensation?", "answer": "A rug", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a5cb", "question": "Which US state is nicknamed the \"Pine Tree State\"?", "answer": "Maine", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339509", "question": "What is the name of John Carpenter's first feature movie?", "answer": "Dark Star", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113393fa", "question": "Which member of the Monkees commonly wore a wool hat?", "answer": "Mike Nesmith", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113393b8", "question": "Which character did Tom Hanks play in the movie \"The Da Vinci Code\"?", "answer": "Robert Langdon", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a26", "question": "What was Barbra Streisand's character's occupation in the movie \"Meet the Fockers\"?", "answer": "Sex therapist", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339bc0", "question": "David Bowie is known for his distinct voice type?", "answer": "Baritone", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd96dca23c87fd04dd15e2f", "question": "Who sculpted Mount Rushmore?", "answer": "Gutzon Borglum", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bae9", "question": "In the Old Testament, who wears his hair in seven braids?", "answer": "Samson", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe7cab9877e98cb97778a0a", "question": "Which river's water is controlled by the Aswan Dam?", "answer": "Nile", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5b571b2e67df192a942e3365", "question": "What year did Cracker Jack introduce their mascots - Sailor Jack and his dog, Bingo?", "answer": "1916", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b7f7", "question": "What sauce is used in traditional eggs Benedict?", "answer": "Hollandaise", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388eb", "question": "What is the dot in the \"i\" called?", "answer": "A tittle", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5e147ab46ca6dac04a20ca50", "question": "Who plays the character \"Eleven\" in the TV show \"Stranger Things\"?", "answer": "Millie Bobby Brown ", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ad7ecafb24f84e0b9f9ffe9", "question": "What is a sphygmomanometer used to measure?", "answer": "Blood pressure", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c2ca", "question": "What is the minimum number of bars on an abacus?", "answer": "Nine", "category": "science"}, {"id": "6015ebcafe83fe1f2a824bfa", "question": "What fall festival activity did the Romans bring to Britain when they invaded?", "answer": "Bobbing for apples", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339574", "question": "In, Santa Baby by Madonna what kind of fur does she want him to slip under the tree?", "answer": "A sable", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fffa73e73838c5c8a417f35", "question": "What is the fertilized egg of a duck called?", "answer": "Balut (Balut is a Filipino term for fertilized duck egg.  It has been a dish in the Philippines for more than 200 years.)", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b5dd", "question": "What were barcodes first used for?", "answer": "To label railroad cars", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f031133895e", "question": "What was Cinderella's real name?", "answer": "Ella", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe3e61438e4e5d4832e6306", "question": "Where were the 1940 Summer Olympics scheduled to be held when they were cancelled due to the outbreak of World War II?", "answer": "Tokyo", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe7beaa877e98cb97778962", "question": "What Hawaiian island is known as \"Bird Island\"?", "answer": "Nihoa", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a394", "question": "What is the largest Scandinavian country?", "answer": "Sweden", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd4a", "question": "By US law, exit signs in buildings must be one of what two colors?", "answer": "Red or green", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fef5e106ce05a3942286e2f", "question": "Which movie\u2019s sequel has the tagline \"Same make. Same model. New mission\"?", "answer": "\"Terminator\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c2d7", "question": "What is the most common atom in the universe?", "answer": "Hydrogen", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113393d8", "question": "From which bridge did Barry Miller fall from in the 1977 movie \"Saturday Night Fever\"?", "answer": "The Verrazano-Narrows Bridge", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c6f", "question": "What was the name of Rhett and Scarlett\u2019s daughter in \"Gone With the Wind\"?", "answer": "Bonnie", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0e8", "question": "Who was Tommy Lee Jones' upperclassman roommate at Harvard?", "answer": "Al Gore", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a165", "question": "Who sings \"Sweet Home Alabama\"?", "answer": "Lynyrd Skynyrd", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6014c4b5fbde8045e48466a0", "question": "What does the African dung beetle use to navigate at night?", "answer": "The Milky Way -- The only animal known to navigate using the Milky Way, they can move objects that are 50 times their weight.", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe8f1cb01dd7bf43be5e808", "question": "Which Crayola color did consumers vote to save from retirement in 2003?", "answer": "Burnt sienna", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113394b9", "question": "What was Peter Gunn's girlfriend's name?", "answer": "Edie Hart", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d51", "question": "What is 007 enemy Dr. No's first name?", "answer": "Julius", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59f9baa1364247bf200fb89a", "question": "What is the fear of death known as?", "answer": "Necrophobia", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b7b5", "question": "What do the letters X.O. stand for on a bottle of cognac?", "answer": "Extra Old", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339068", "question": "What is the name of the dog from the story \"How the Grinch Stole Christmas\"?", "answer": "Max", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ff14066b0ee8c595b6d399c", "question": "Which 1920s play is the first major play written for children?", "answer": "\"Peter Pan\"", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e68", "question": "Who provided the original voice for Yogi Bear?", "answer": "Daws Butler", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bcee", "question": "What operation, consisting of a laparotomy and a hysterotomy, is the most commonly performed procedure in US hospitals?", "answer": "A caesarean section", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe7cb6f877e98cb97778a1a", "question": "In which country are you likely to hear the cheer or toast \"Opa!\" during a celebration?", "answer": "Greece", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113399f3", "question": "What famous TV cops drove a 1974 Ford Torino?", "answer": "Starsky & Hutch", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c212", "question": "Which country were the 1928 Winter Olympic Games held in?", "answer": "Switzerland", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b275", "question": "What disease grounded astronaut Ken Mattingly from Apollo 13?", "answer": "The measles", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bbcd", "question": "In what year did Joseph Smith first organize the Mormon Church?", "answer": "1830", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe7be9f877e98cb97778961", "question": "What mountain range stretches from the town of Seesen in northwest Germany to Eisleben in the east?", "answer": "Harz", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c15d", "question": "Which city is served by Schwechat airport?", "answer": "Vienna", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113397e7", "question": "Which film mogul was famous for illogical sayings such as \"include me out\"?", "answer": "Sam Goldwyn", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ae860a84007905755f79e8f", "question": "What year was Julius Caeser assassinated", "answer": "44 BC", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ffa4023c73aa70ea0b70b08", "question": "From 1964 to 1980, what country was known as Rhodesia?", "answer": "Zimbabwe", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ccf7bb0b37b32637bdc44c6", "question": "In what year was the language learning site/app Duolingo launched?", "answer": "2011", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a45d", "question": "The island country Grenada is also known as what?", "answer": "Island of Spice", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ff25a4331a458464a93c46f", "question": "What is the process called by which people set out to amass large amounts of in-game currency to sell in the real world?", "answer": "Gold farming", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5904a471cf93664eb10486c3", "question": "In the comic book series \"Strangers in Paradise\", what is Katchoo\u2019s full name?", "answer": "Katina Marie Choovanski", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a4d0", "question": "Which US president on Mount Rushmore has a mustache?", "answer": "Theodore Roosevelt", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113396c7", "question": "What baseball team did Cheers' manager Sam Malone play for in the TV show?", "answer": "The Boston Red Sox", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133929e", "question": "In \"Ferris Bueller's Day Off\", who is the \"Sausage King of Chicago\"?", "answer": "Abe Froman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e6b", "question": "Who painted \"Carnation, Lily, Lily, Rose\"?", "answer": "John Singer Sargent", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "6015e763fe83fe1f2a824bd2", "question": "Although never taking her seat, who was the first woman to be elected to the houses of parliament in Europe?", "answer": "Countess Markievicz", "category": "history"}, {"id": "6015f82dfe83fe1f2a824c29", "question": "When was Queen Elizabeth II born?", "answer": "She was born on April 21, 1926 at 2:40 A.M.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339977", "question": "In the TV show \"The Simpsons\", Lenny has a master's degree in what field?", "answer": "Nuclear Physics", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff0afcae662d71a53650fc3", "question": "Who is Fridwulfa the mother of?", "answer": "Rubeus Hagrid", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59029db7cad1ec93f27df751", "question": "What popular French apple brandy is made by distilling cider made from selected apples?", "answer": "Calvados", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58c8a8b090aac110e4167091", "question": "In the North American market, what is the difference between hard and sweet cider?", "answer": "Hard cider is alcoholic while sweet cider is not", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f83", "question": "What was Balki's home island on TV's \"Perfect Strangers\"?", "answer": "Mypos", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c1ed", "question": "What cocktail is considered the official cocktail of New Orleans?", "answer": "Sazerac", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5b57183c67df192a942e335c", "question": "Which stretch of water seperates Tierra del Fuego from the rest of South America?", "answer": "Strait of Magellan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ecae22b790ded87bb38fd87", "question": "Who directed the seminal 1972 science-fiction film Solaris?", "answer": "Andrei Tarkovsky", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5febd3eb7e83c707845b2157", "question": "Red had how many parole hearings through out the course of the movie \"The Shawshank Redemption\"?", "answer": "Three", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe65797ae7e414034b5aede", "question": "Facebook co-founder Sean Parker was also the co-founder of which company?", "answer": "Napster", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133adaa", "question": "The \"Indus Valley Civilization\" is also known by what other name?", "answer": "Harappan Civilization", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59cdb2af65ff7d326b622a77", "question": "Mycophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Mushrooms", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b194", "question": "What year did Napoleon become King of Italy?", "answer": "1805", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a262", "question": "What is the name of the summer camp in the \"Friday the 13th\" movie series?", "answer": "Camp Crystal Lake\u00a0", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a06c", "question": "Which duo released albums called \"Introspective\" and \"Very\"?", "answer": "Pet Shop Boys", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "594a633f2ebb971c1417fb98", "question": "Which Queen of England, and wife of Henry VIII, had six fingers on one of her hands?", "answer": "Anne Boleyn", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c994", "question": "What was Marie Curie's husbands name?", "answer": "Pierre", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a5b6", "question": "Which US state is nicknamed the \"Old Dominion\" state?", "answer": "Virginia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e17", "question": "What French Wave director plays the UFO expert in \"Close Encounters of the Third Kind\"?", "answer": "Francois Truffaut", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd66638a5bfecdd737e0867", "question": "What color is second from the top in a rainbow?", "answer": "Orange", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b51d", "question": "What are the two basic types of Scotch Whisky?", "answer": "Single Malt and Single Grain", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fd66377a5bfecdd737e0850", "question": "How long have dogs been domesticated?", "answer": "15,000 years", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339020", "question": "Which US author penned the novels \"Of Mice and Men\" and \"East Of Eden\"?", "answer": "John Steinbeck", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c2c8", "question": "What fruit is packed with the most calories?", "answer": "The avocado", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388ad", "question": "What nationality was Pablo Picasso?", "answer": "Spanish", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a25", "question": "What are Hall & Oates' first names?", "answer": "Daryl and John", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe6a5d020565ad31a57c7d1", "question": "Seeds for what fruit were found in King Tut\u2019s tomb?", "answer": "Watermelon", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5909cfcfbb53d1af658864f6", "question": "What is the curved part of the candy cane known as?", "answer": "The warble", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d4d", "question": "What actress shaved her head for her role in the movie \"Caged\"?", "answer": "Eleanor Parker", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fefc1036ce05a3942286f0c", "question": "In the film \"Gladiator,\" Maximus hails from what country?", "answer": "Spain", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a952", "question": "What is the only US state that ends with the state's own postal abbreviation?", "answer": "Kentucky", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59523fde736d4be723796b5c", "question": "What year was Hudson\u2019s Bay Company founded?", "answer": "1670", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c1ec", "question": "What is added to cognac and absinthe to make a Sazerac cocktail?", "answer": "Sugar cube and Peychaud's bitters", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5989aa3ccb8751d53e7d7602", "question": "Who served as the United States Ambassador to Japan from 2013-2017?", "answer": "Caroline Bouvier Kennedy", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113397d3", "question": "What country singer released the album \"Pieces of the Sky\"?", "answer": "Emmylou Harris", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff14679b0ee8c595b6d39c0", "question": "What classic book inspired the name of Starbucks?", "answer": "Moby Dick", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c6f9", "question": "What is the correct name for a baby seal, baby shark, or baby bat?", "answer": "Pup", "category": "science"}, {"id": "58b8d47f2b42d4a3561a9efa", "question": "In the comic book series \"Strangers in Paradise\", who did Katchoo visit when she disappeared in Canada for 2 months?", "answer": "Emma", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c492", "question": "The word \"laser\" stands for what?", "answer": "Light Amplification by Stimulated Emission of Radiation", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133acfa", "question": "What disability did Thomas Edison have?", "answer": "He was hearing impaired", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe65805ae7e414034b5aee5", "question": "In the Bible in the book of Job, who begins the first discourse to Job?", "answer": "Eliphaz", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b9ee", "question": "How many vehicles did the second \"Gran Turismo\" video game have?", "answer": "650", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b74e", "question": "What is the highest number on a standard roulette wheel?", "answer": "36", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a5c2", "question": "Which two US states begin with the letter \"V\"?", "answer": "Vermont and Virginia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338fe3", "question": "In which book did four ghosts visit Scrooge?", "answer": "A Christmas Carol", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "600cc8816de0eb824d4052fc", "question": "What is Camp David's official name?", "answer": "Naval Support Facility Thurmont -- President Eisenhower named it Camp David after his grandson, David.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca50", "question": "Honeydew is a variety of what?", "answer": "Melon", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133abf2", "question": "In what sort of landscape would you find an erg?", "answer": "Desert", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf82", "question": "What country celebrates its National Day on 14th July?", "answer": "France", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b976", "question": "Which religious ceremony comes from the Greek word meaning \"to dip\"?", "answer": "Baptism", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58f16aa7f7c52aae91cc07df", "question": "In which city is the \"Wailing Wall\"?", "answer": "Jerusalem", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "58b0e9cc964118b2bb3809cd", "question": "Who is the Greek counterpart to Cupid?", "answer": "Eros", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113392c8", "question": "Who authored the song \"In the Ghetto\"?", "answer": "Mac Davis", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ffb67445dad637d903c883c", "question": "What country\u2019s land is mostly on an island, although most of its people live on a peninsula across the South China Sea?", "answer": "Malaysia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b35a", "question": "Who found the long lost explorer David Livingston?", "answer": "Henry Morton Stanley", "category": "history"}, {"id": "6016011efe83fe1f2a824c5b", "question": "Which company manufactured the film for NASA\u2019s Apollo 11 moon mission?", "answer": "Kodak", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a80a", "question": "What country controls the Mediterranean island of Corsica?", "answer": "France", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c6ca", "question": "A tree which is deciduous does what?", "answer": "Loses its leaves every year", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339be3", "question": "In what year was actor Johnny Depp born?", "answer": "1963", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133aec3", "question": "Who created the New Model Army?", "answer": "Oliver Cromwell", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fd66cd0a5bfecdd737e0898", "question": "Which letter starts the fewest words in the English language?", "answer": "X", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f4d", "question": "An episode of what sitcom spawned the phrase \"jumped the shark\"?", "answer": "Happy Days", "category": "entertainment"}]